<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on R Things on Nicholas Vietto </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on R Things on Nicholas Vietto </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding hex codes and col2hcl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/col2hcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/col2hcl/</guid>
      <description>What are hex codes? Hexadecimals, or &amp;lsquo;hex codes,&amp;rsquo; operate on a number system with a base value of 16, hence the term &amp;lsquo;hex.&amp;rsquo; In R, we use them to integrate colors into plots, presentations, websites or really anything. These codes represent colors through a blend of red, green, and blue (RGB) values, where each color is denoted by a two-digit hexadecimal number ranging from 00 (representing the absence of color) to FF (representing the maximum intensity).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using pacman::p_load()</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/pacmanp_load/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/pacmanp_load/</guid>
      <description>Loading and installing multiple packages can take up time and space at the beginning of your scripts, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to R and still getting familiar with what each package does.&#xA;For example, the beginning of my homework assignments in my second semester of Advance Statistics would often look like this:&#xA;# install.packages(&amp;#34;&amp;#34;) library(haven) library(tidyr) library(readr) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(tigerstats) library(lattice) library(grid) library(mosaic) library(pastecs) library(car) library (multcomp) library(granova) library(polycor) library(yarrr) Which not only looks silly but also takes a significant amount of time to install each individually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping HTML Tables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/webscraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/webscraping/</guid>
      <description>If you share my passion for NFL stats, you might have considered getting some data to analyze or even predict outcomes. Instead of tediously inputting data into Excel, you can opt for a more efficient method - web scraping with {rvest} in R.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s scrape the career stats of Jared Goff from the Detroit Lions 🦁&#xA;Set up &amp;amp; Scrape Lets install and load our packages.&#xA;We will need the tidyverse, rvest, and janitor packages.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
