<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on R Things on Nicholas Vietto </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on R Things on Nicholas Vietto </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing {samplezoo}</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/samplezoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/samplezoo/</guid>
      <description>While preparing lecture materials for undergraduate statistics, I often found myself repeatedly looking up code documentation on how to generate distributions. This might just be a &amp;lsquo;me problem&amp;rsquo; — having the memory of a goldfish (no offense to any goldfish reading this 😅) — but I figured, &amp;ldquo;Hey, maybe someone else has this issue too.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;So, I developed {samplezoo} to save time and help educators focus more on creatively teaching statistical concepts rather than spending that time on setup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>{Rdune} is now on CRAN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/rdune2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/rdune2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to announce that {Rdune} has been published on CRAN🎉. What does that mean exactly? And what&amp;rsquo;s next for {Rdune}? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into it.&#xA;What is CRAN? CRAN (Comprehensive R Archive Network), maintained by the R Foundation for Statistical Computing, is the primary repository for R packages. It provides storage, distribution, and documentation for R software and its extensions, ensuring consistency and availability of packages across various systems and platforms, including Windows, macOS, and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing {Rdune}</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/rdune/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/rdune/</guid>
      <description>Want to add some &amp;lsquo;spice&amp;rsquo; to your {ggplot2} data visualizations? You&amp;rsquo;re in the right place! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to introduce {Rdune}, a collection of 15 color palettes inspired by &amp;lsquo;Dune&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Image: giphy.com How to install and load Currently, only the developmental version of {Rdune} is available on GitHub. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with how to download a developmental version of an R library, simply follow these steps:&#xA;Install {devtools} install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) Load {devtools} library(devtools) Install {Rdune} from GitHub devtools::install_github(&amp;#34;nvietto/Rdune&amp;#34;) Load {Rdune} library(Rdune) Now that {Rdune} is installed, you can load it like any other R library in the future using library(Rdune).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding hex codes and col2hcl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/col2hcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/col2hcl/</guid>
      <description>What are hex codes? Hexadecimals, or &amp;lsquo;hex codes,&amp;rsquo; operate on a number system with a base value of 16, hence the term &amp;lsquo;hex.&amp;rsquo; In R, we use them to integrate colors into plots, presentations, websites or really anything. These codes represent colors through a blend of red, green, and blue (RGB) values, where each color is denoted by a two-digit hexadecimal number ranging from 00 (representing the absence of color) to FF (representing the maximum intensity).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using pacman::p_load()</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/pacmanp_load/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/pacmanp_load/</guid>
      <description>Loading and installing multiple packages can take up time and space at the beginning of your scripts, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to R and still getting familiar with what each package does.&#xA;For example, the beginning of my homework assignments in my second semester of Advance Statistics would often look like this:&#xA;# install.packages(&amp;#34;&amp;#34;) library(haven) library(tidyr) library(readr) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(tigerstats) library(lattice) library(grid) library(mosaic) library(pastecs) library(car) library (multcomp) library(granova) library(polycor) library(yarrr) Which not only looks silly but also takes a significant amount of time to install each individually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping HTML Tables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/webscraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/webscraping/</guid>
      <description>If you share my passion for the NFL, you may have considered finding some NFL data to analyze. Instead of manually inputting data into Excel, you can use a more efficient method: web scraping with the {rvest} package in R.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s scrape the career stats of Jared Goff from my favorite team - the Detroit Lions 🦁&#xA;Set up &amp;amp; Scrape Lets install and load our packages.&#xA;We will need the tidyverse, rvest, and janitor packages.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
