<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nicholas Vietto </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nicholas Vietto </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/teaching/</guid>
      <description>This page provides teaching materials for the courses I&amp;rsquo;ve developed and taught. Below, you&amp;rsquo;ll find links to slides, assignments, and additional resources. Feel free to use and share them.&#xA;Research Methods This is an undergraduate criminology and criminal justice research methods course. The course material was adapted from CRCJ 2510 Research Methods course.&#xA;GitHub: https://github.com/nvietto/Teaching/tree/main/CRCJ-2510&#xA;Applied Statistics This is an undergraduate criminology and criminal justice applied statistics course.&#xA;GitHub: https://github.com/nvietto/Teaching/tree/main/CRCJ-3000</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/publications/</guid>
      <description>Below, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a list of my publications. It&amp;rsquo;s on my to do list to make these accessible on an open-access platform, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to reach out if you encounter a paywall and require a copy. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help.&#xA;Biopsychosocial Criminology Vietto, N., Armstrong, T.A., Schroll, D., &amp;amp; Al Falatah, S. (2024). Differences in associations between autonomic nervous system activity and psychopathic traits across stress paradigms and psychopathy measures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/data-visulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/data-visulation/</guid>
      <description>TidyTuesday is a weekly social data challenge in R, where participants use a new data set each week to create a data visualization and share their work on social media with #TidyTuesday. For more information on how to participate head here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Packages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/packages/</guid>
      <description>samplezoo The {samplezoo} package simplifies generating samples with various probability distributions, enabling users to quickly create data frames for demonstrations, troubleshooting, or teaching. By prioritizing simplicity and speed over customization of sample parameters, {samplezoo} reduces the need for repetitive code, making it particularly useful for beginners or anyone seeking to save time while working with statistical and probabilistic data.&#xA;GitHub: https://nvietto.github.io/samplezoo/&#xA;Rdune The {Rdune} package offers a collection of color palettes inspired by &amp;lsquo;Dune&amp;rsquo;, designed for use in data visualizations and graphics with {ggplot2}.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
