<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nicholas Vietto </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nicholas Vietto </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/teaching/</guid>
      <description>This page contains the teaching material for courses I have taught and developed. At the links below, you&amp;rsquo;ll find slides, assignments, and other resources. Feel free to use them.&#xA;Research Methods This is an undergraduate criminology and criminal justice research methods course.&#xA;The repository for course material can be found here.&#xA;Statistics This is an undergraduate criminology and criminal justice applied statistics course.&#xA;The repository for course material can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/publications/</guid>
      <description>Below, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a list of my publications. While it&amp;rsquo;s on my to do list to make them accessible on an open-access platform, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to reach out if you encounter a paywall and require a copy. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help.&#xA;Biopsychosocial Criminology Armstrong, T. A., Boisvert, D. L., Wells, J., Lewis, R. H., Cooke, E. M., Woeckener, M., Kavish, N., Vietto, N., &amp;amp; Harper, J. M. (2022). Testosterone, cortisol, and criminal behavior in men and women.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/data-visulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/data-visulation/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday is a weekly social data challenge in R, where participants use a new data set each week to create a data visualization and share their work on social media with #TidyTuesday. For more information on how to participate head here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Packages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/packages/</guid>
      <description>These are some fun packages I&amp;rsquo;ve created for R users.&#xA;nopunintended nopunintended is a package designed to take your mind off coding with puns from &amp;lsquo;No Pun Intended: Volume Too&amp;rsquo; in the show/video game &amp;lsquo;The Last of Us&amp;rsquo;. Check it out here.&#xA;movienight movienight is a package that recommend a film within RStudio. Check it out here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
